Filipe Teixeira Amaral

Python Full Stack Engineer

Address Belo Horizonte, MG, Brazil

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/itisfilipe/

Phone 5532988794370

E-mail filipetamaral@gmail.com

Well-qualified Senior Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Able to handle any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 6+ years of related experience and currently working with Django, VueJs, and AWS.

Work History

2019-04 - Current

Senior Full Stack Engineer

BriteCore, Remote

- Helped to replace the existing system functionality with modern and flexible modular components made with Python, Django, Flask, and VueJS, deployed on AWS.
- Developed (as part of an three-person engineering team) a custom serverless Authentication service that offers standard auth, social auth, SSO and MFA to 50+ insurance companies.

2018-01 - 2019-03

Lead Software Engineer

BriteCore, Remote

- Led a team of four engineers to integrate a new insurance client to our SaaS platform.
- Helped to translate client requirements into technical specifications.
- Performed code reviews and trained new engineers.
- Through our platform, the client sold over U\$2M in premium to 500+ insured customers.

2017-08 - 2017-12

Full Stack Engineer

BriteCore, Remote

- Collaborated with developers to maintain a legacy project made with Web.py, Knockout.js, VanillaJS, and pure Python APIs.
- Offered support to existent clients by analyzing use cases, proposing new features, and fixing existing bugs.

2016-06 - 2017-06

Frontend Engineer

localhost.company, Slovakia/Remote

- Cooperated with three engineers in building the frontend of an online market place with Angular 1.
- Collaborated with two engineers to migrate a Google Docs alike platform, from Angular 1 to Angular 2.
- Worked in their headquarters in Slovakia for three months and then remotely until the end of the contract.

2014-04 - 2016-06 Full Stack Engineer

UFSJ, Brazil

- Refactored the interface of our online educational platform helping 1k+ teachers and 15k+ students access their lessons.
- Architected and developed (three-person team) an educational platform for primary school students, using Flask, jQuery, and Bootstrap.
- Collaborated with senior analysts to identify and resolve bugs on the university's educational platform (PHP/Moodle).

Education

2012-01 - 2016-01 Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Universidade Federal De São João Del-Rei - São João Del-Rei

Certifications

2019-12 AWS CERTIFIED DEVELOPER - ASSOCIATE

Https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/2b36f53a-6b4c-4404-bca9-d966614197fb

Skills

Flask/Django/Web.py/Python

Vuejs/AngularJs/KnockoutJs/TypeScript/JavaScript

MySQL/PostgreSQL

HTML/CSS

AWS/Docker/Serverless

Projects

Quiz App | Django, React, Django Rest Framework, Docker

An over-engineered quiz app to show off some skills in Django and React. https://github.com/Itisfilipe/quizApp

Feature Requests App | Flask, KnockoutJs, Bootstrap, SQLAlchemy

Feature requests app intended to practice some skills in flask and knockoutJs. https://github.com/ltisfilipe/feature-requets-flask-app

SFN Workload | Lambda, DynamoDB, CloudWatch, SES, Step Functions

An AWS workload that collects, processes, and delivers data through a series of lambda functions.

https://github.com/Itisfilipe/sfn-workload

Keyboard Sounds | TypeScript, VSCode API

VSCode extension that reproduces mechanical keyboard sounds and has over 3k downloads.

https://github.com/Itisfilipe/keyboard-sounds